Dom Finlay

Web Developer

SUMMARY

Self-taught Web Developer seeking a junior position. Proficient in Python, Javascript, HTML, and CSS, and some familiarity with many other languages and frameworks, including React, SQLite, jQuery, and more. My non-traditional background has given me an array of soft skills that compliment my coding, including four years' experience teaching English in South Korea, which tested resolve, resilience, and determination.

PROJECTS

Ideabot: Ideabot helps those learning to code by providing coding project ideas in a simple, easy-to-digest manner. Simply input your interests and let some Javascript, CSS, HTML, and OpenAl API do the rest.

Portfolio Website: Creating my personal portfolio website (<u>domfinlay.dev</u>) pushed me to improve my web development skills considerably. I tried to convey my personality in the design while maintaining its functionality.

Pass the Ball - The ESL Game Database: Using a wide variety of tools, *Pass the Ball* is a full-stack web app allowing ESL (English as a Second Language) teachers to add and browse games in an SQLite database.

Smaller projects (React Pomodoro Timer, React Calculator, React Drum Machine, Markdown Previewer): Created in order to learn React, jQuery, and other front-end tools, as well as my eye for design, these projects all presented difficult challenges despite their simple presentation.

EXPERIENCE

Chungbuk International Education Institute, Okcheon - Head English Teacher

(Aug 2020 - Aug 2022) Led a team of three teachers in planning, preparing, and teaching specialised, original lessons to students of all ages.

Getintothis, Liverpool — Volunteer Writer (Jul 2018 - Mar 2019)

Researched and wrote news articles, lists, guides, reviews for a local music website.

Various Schools, Daegu — *Native English Teacher (*Feb 2016 - Feb 2018)

Planned and taught English lessons, exams, and extracurricular activities for elementary and middle schools.

EDUCATION

Lancaster University (September 2012 - Jun 2015) - 2:1 English Literature BA (Hons)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Korean Language (Advanced)
- Photography